<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[My Octopress Blog]]></title>
  <link href="http://grigy.heroku.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://grigy.heroku.com/"/>
  <updated>2012-01-29T12:18:54+04:00</updated>
  <id>http://grigy.heroku.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Grigor Yeghiazaryan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Why I Write]]></title>
    <link href="http://grigy.heroku.com/blog/2012/01/28/why-i-write/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-28T18:55:00+04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grigy.heroku.com/blog/2012/01/28/why-i-write</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The simple answer is because I feel I need to. But you are not here for that answer.</p>

<p>There are many write-ups about why should someone blog. They cover both objective and subjective benefits of blogging. This is not a generalization of these ideas. Here I want to talk about my personal reasons, the ones to which I came myself while learning through living my life.</p>

<p>Here are 5 reasons from the top of my head:</p>

<h3>I get it better if I write it down</h3>

<p>Since college years I noticed that when I write my ideas I get them better. Later I realized how it works.</p>

<p>When you write about something you need to think of every detail of it, make logical connections between pieces and represent it in a simple, readable form. And while performing these steps you think about the subject deeper, from different angles and as a result you get it better.</p>

<p>Since then whenever I want to crack complex subjects down I write them.</p>

<h3>Writing improves my writing skills</h3>

<p>I want to be good at English writing. Not good, even better.</p>

<p>The single most effective way of mastering something is constant practicing. And how do you practice writing? Right, by writing. But people normally don&#8217;t write much during the day, of course if that&#8217;s not what they do for living. I also don&#8217;t write much at my job.</p>

<p>So blogging makes a perfect sense to me for improving my writing skills.</p>

<h3>I want to share my knowledge</h3>

<p>Really, I want to share what I know to help others.</p>

<p>And I truly believe that it is also for my own sake. If people around me know as much as I do, then I need to learn even more to catch them up. This is a little secret tool to keep me in constant learning loop.</p>

<p>Actually I think knowledge sharing is a powerful motivator for constant learning.</p>

<h3>I want people to know me</h3>

<p>Ideally when meeting new people I would let them know my blog&#8217;s URL and they could learn about me eventually. In reality no one is going to read all the stuff I&#8217;m putting up here. Even if some of them do, I&#8217;m not going to write about everything.</p>

<p>But the blog can be used to express my opinion on a particular subject. Whenever they want my opinion on a subject, a blog post can be the answer. And the URL of the post can be thrown in for discussion. I find this an effective way of getting others to know me.</p>

<h3>I want to get followers</h3>

<p>I would like to be famous. Not kind of star-famous. Simply get like-minded people to read my blog regularly. Why do I need this? Come on, you know why. Read the about page again, I&#8217;m bootstraping my startups and I need to spread the word.</p>

<p>I belive if I post interesting and quality content regularly I may have a chance to get my followers.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Resurrection]]></title>
    <link href="http://grigy.heroku.com/blog/2012/01/28/resurrection/"/>
    <updated>2012-01-28T17:21:00+04:00</updated>
    <id>http://grigy.heroku.com/blog/2012/01/28/resurrection</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Finally I decided to give another shot to blogging. This is my third attempt.</p>

<p>If you skim over the previous blogs, you will see that it becomes more serious with every new attempt. And hopefully this time it&#8217;s already at the level of seriousness that I&#8217;ll stick to it.</p>

<p>Crossing fingers and stopping breath for a moment I think loudly &#8220;promise to take care of this one&#8221;.</p>

<p>More technically, I&#8217;m just writing something to test out this new blogging platform that I choose to make my life more difficult.</p>

<p>In short, Welcome!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
